

ANTRA TRIPATHI

B.Tech CSE Undergraduate
Data Science Enthusiast

CONTACT

Mobile: 9454845284

Email:

antra.tripathi@st.niituniversity.in

SOCIAL MEDIA

Linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/antra-tripathi

Facebook:

www.facebook.com/antra.tripathi

Instagram:

www.instagram.com/antratripathi/







PROFILE

I am currently pursuing B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering from NIIT University with specialization in domain of Data Science. I like programming and exploring new technologies. I am a keen observer and a quick learner. To quench my curiosity I keep trying and learning new stuff on my own. I am a confident, passionate and hard working girl in technology, who tries to bring best out of whatever she does. My leadership qualities give me an upper hand. Apart from these I am a Photographer and an Artist at heart too!

EXPERIENCE

PHOTOGRAPHY CLUB LEAD

NIIT UNIVERSITY | JAN 2018 - DEC 2018

- Official Photographer of the University
- Handling University's Photography Portfolio
- Organizing Photography Exhibition and Annual Photography trip

CREATIVE HEAD- SINUSOID'17

NIIT UNIVERSITY | JAN 2017 - JAN 2018

- siNUsoid is the Annual Technical Festival of NIIT University started last year by a bung of tech enthusiast.
- I was the one of the founding member of siNUsoid'17.
- We try to build a platform which provides an opportunity for every necessity to become an invention.

MEMBER OF PRESIDENT ADVISORY BOARD

NIIT UNIVERSITY | SEP 2016 - PRESENT

- Student representative to the President of the University
- Bringing up student issues to the President.
- Help in drafting and developing efficient solutions for them.
- MOM keeper

FIREFOX STUDENT AMBASSADOR

MOZILLA | MAR 2016 - DEC 2017

- Obtain roles on campus and in Mozilla community
- Work with other tech community and Mozilla staff to organize technical events, and creating awareness about open source society.

STUDENT MENTOR- INDUCTION PROGRAM

NIIT UNIVERSITY | JULY 2016 - JUNE 2017

 Providing guidance to the new B.Tech Undergraduate of class of 2016.

CAMPUS AMBASSADOR- IRIS 2016

IIM INDORE | OCT 2016 -NOV 2016

 IRIS- The Cultural and Management fest of IIM -I. I was chosen as campus ambassador for promoting this event in our college NIIT University.

SKILLS

Python

Java

- Machine Learning
- Android Development
- HTML5/CSS3
- C\C++

OTHER SKILLS:

- Photography
- Leadership Qualities
- Creative and Artistic

Sports

PROJECTS DONE

• R&D: KERNEL LEVEL IMPLEMENTATION OF HADOOP | JAN 2018

Hadoop is an open source, Java-based programming framework that supports the processing and storage of extremely large data sets in a distributed system. So the motive of this research is to find why it is not implemented at kernel level, what are the difficulties and how to implement it.

• CAPSTONE: COMMUNITY PORTAL | JAN 2018

To build an interactive and dynamic coding/blog platform where we can share/reuse the written code. The aim of the project would be to build a WebApp(Website) for putting learnt codes/Algorithms /knowledge repository live for everyone to use.

• UIDAI AADHAR DATASET ANANLYSIS | JAN 2018

This project was part of the course big data concepts. The aim of the project was to analyze the aadhar dataset of more than 5 lakh records using Hadoop MapReduce and Hive.

• ENCRYPTION DECRYPTION TOOL | OCT 2017

Keeping this real life problem in mind we have decided to make a tool which can encrypt and decrypt a specific file. Language used is Java and Javafx. Techniques: caesarCipher, vigereneCipher, transpositionCipher and Blow-fish.

VITT: DAY TO DAY PERSON FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT APPLICATION | OCT 2017

VITT is an simple Android Application which is aimed toward those users who would like to keep a track of their day to day personal finance. Easy operable, with no dependency on any other software.

• DATABASE FOR MANAGING STUDENT INFORMATION IN COLLEGE | JAN 2016

Student Information Database System (SIDS) - provides a simple interface for maintaining the student's record (both academics and non-academics), created using MySql RDBMS and optimised using different normalisation techniques.

• VOICE CONTROLLED BOT | OCT 2016

This project was part of my DLC(digital logic circuit). We made a voice controlled bot using Ardunio UNO and bluetooth odule HC-05. This bot executed the voice command into mechanical movements. It has nine functionality

PBL- INFLATION IN HOTEL INDUSTRY | MAR 2016

PBL is a project based learning assignment in Economics. My topic was Inflation in Indian Hotel Industry, in which I had to come up with case study on the given topic with supporting statistical data.

EDUCATION

BTECH CSE, SPECIALIZATION IN DATA SCIENCE

NIIT UVIVERSITY | 2015 - 2019 CGPA: 7.75

INTERMEDIATE - ISC

IPEM INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL | 2013 - 2015 Percentage: 90%

HIGH SCHOOL - ICSE

IPEM INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL | 2004 - 2013 Percentage: 89%

INTERNSHIP TRAINING

ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

TECHNEX -IIT BHU | JUNE 2017- JULY 2017

Android App Development: Using Eclipse and Android Studio

ONLINE TRAINING

MACHINE LEARNING FOUNDATION NANODEGREE PROGRAM

UDACITY | JAN 2018- APR 2018

Python Programming, Descriptive Statistics, Linear Algebra, Inferential statistics, Evaluation and Verification

HADOOP FOUNDATION- LEVEL 1

IBM- COGNITIVE CLASS | JAN 2018

Basis of Hadoop architecture and Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) using IBM BigInsights.

BIG DATA FOUNDATION-LEVEL 1

IBM- COGNITIVE CLASS | JAN 2018

Basis understanding of Big Data concepts and their applications

NPTEL ONLINE CERTIFICATION

SOFT SKILLS | NOV 2017

Soft skill course designed by IIT-Roorkee

COMPLETE ANDROID N DEVELOPER COURSE

UDEMY | SEP 2017

Android App Development: Android Studio

HTML AND CSS FOR BEGINNERS - BUILD A WEBSITE & LAUNCH

UDEMY | FEB 2017

Learned HTML, CSS and Java script